<ggobidata count="3">

<data name="nodes">
<description>
  These are the points that define the polygons in the map.
  They are not data points per se, and we have no interest
  in plotting them in a conventional ggobi scatterplot,
  because it's the polygons we're interested in and not the
  nodes or edges.

  In that sense, it's a bit of a kludge to use this very
  general setup to define a map.

  There might be a very large number of nodes.
</description>

<variables count="2">
  <realvariable name="latitude" />
  <realvariable name="longitude" />
</variables>

<records count="40000">
 <record id="0"> 2 4 </record>
 <record id="1"> 3 5 </record>
 <record id="2"> 4 7 </record>
 ...
</records>

<data name="polygons">
<description>
  These are the polygon definitions, which are made by listing
  some number of ids defined in the nodes datad.

  A group of polygons taken together may define a political entity
  (think of the islands of Hawaii) so we may still need a third datad
  to specify those entities.

  In any case, we may have variables on these polygons -- categorical
  variables defining geographic entities, or other data.

  This is an odd datad from the point of view of ggobi -- ggobi,
  excluding the plugin, might want to read the variables on the
  polygon records, but it should ignore the geometric information.
</description>

<variables count="1">
  <categorical variable name="state">
    <levels count="50">
      <level value="0"> Hawaii </level>
      <level value="1"> Alaska </level>
      ...
     </levels>
  </categoricalvariable>
</variables>
  
<records count="60">
<record label="Oahu" polygonpts="4" pt="1" pt="2" pt="3" pt="7"> 0 </record>
<record label="Lanai" polygonpts="4" pt="1" pt="2" pt="3" pt="7"> 0 </record>
...
</records>
</data>


<data name="state data">
<description>
  This third datad contains the covariates on the data, the variables
  measured for each state.  This is the only one of the three that
  is unambiguously of interest to ggobi without the plugin.
</description>

<variables count="6">
  <categorical variable name="state">
    <levels count="50">
      <level value="0"> Hawaii </level>
      <level value="1"> Alaska </level>
      ...
     </levels>
  </categoricalvariable>
  <realvariable name="rainfall" />
  <realvariable name="min temp" />
  ...
</variables>
  
<records count="50">
<record label="Hawaii"> 0 600  42 ... </record>
<record label="Alaska"> 1 200 -60 ... </record>
...
</records>
</data>

</ggobidata>
